<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[installgentoo_status]]></title>
  <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-17T02:54:28+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[bananafish]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to some long time staff members.]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/thanks-to-some-long-time-staff-members/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/10/14/thanks-to-some-long-time-staff-members</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><div>Today we say goodbye to two great and long time staff members of /g/tracker and other InstallGentoo services. <a href="http://gtracker.installgentoo.com/user.php?id=13">dellfag</a> and <a href="http://gtracker.installgentoo.com/user.php?id=10">pictron</a> have been with installgentoo since the early days of the tracker and have helped to build this community in to what it is today. Hanging the Staff Jacket up on the rack, they will be the first to take the Legend jacket off the wall and start wearing it with pride. Please stop in to this thread to wish them both well.</div></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moving of the status blog.]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/10/13/moving-of-the-status-blog/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/10/13/moving-of-the-status-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our status blog has been moved an reworked countless times, and this is just another one of those times.</p>


<p>I have moved it to, yes, loltumblr.  For a few reasons&#8230;</p>


<p>First being I strongly feel that blogger is gonna get the axe one of these days, its stale, its stagnant, and just all around shit.  I can easily see google pulling the plug.</p>


<p>Next tumblr and newer blogging platforms have better integration with social media and other things. As well as just being all around newer, fresher and better feeling.</p>


<p>Some of you may be asking, like many others have, why I am not hosting my own blog.  Well if something happens, to say, all of the servers how would I let you know?</p>


<p>So for now we are on tumblr, I am silently contemplating moving to wordpress.com but tumblr is good enough for now.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New main site.]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/new-main-site/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/new-main-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have switched us over to our new website, I regular change websites and I don&#8217;<br/>t know why.  We will be sticking with this site for awhile because I really like werc.  Also we will be changing the colors soon.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FTP connecting issues]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/ftp-connecting-issues/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/ftp-connecting-issues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It came to my attention that sometime last night users were having trouble connecting to the FTP server. After looking into this vsftpd seems to be having issues, and specifically issues with the version packaged for debian wheezy.<br/><br/>To resolve this I have moved us over a different daemon, until vsftpd can get fixed.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public Statement Regarding the FTP and etc.]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/22/public-statement-regarding-the-ftp-and-etc/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/22/public-statement-regarding-the-ftp-and-etc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay since I have been asking several times about what is going on, I have decided to post a statement about our FTP service.<br/><br/>First a little back story&#8230;<br/><br/>There was a new #/g/tracker user/member who showed up around a month ago.  This user/member was a very odd user who often brought up arguments on strange topics.  <br/><br/>This member while a nuisance was tolerated as we are not an elitist group that silences people that annoy us.<br/><br/>Until this member, dropped dox on another member and attempted to on two other staff members.  This is not tolerated in our humble community and he was banned.  His /g/mail was also disabled in the process.<br/><br/>This made the now bannished member upset and he decided to report our FTP service to our hosting provider and to some copyright watchdog groups.  Thus unleashing a huge shit storm upon /g/ and installgentoo.com community.<br/><br/>So the staff and myself went into containment mode, our primary irc channel was on lock down, the ftp was turned off and our main site was changed.  <br/><br/>That is entire story, anything else was pure speculation or lie.<br/><br/><br/>Today the staff has made some decisions on how things will be changed from now on.<br/><br/></p>


<ul><li>First ftp access will be brought back shortly though with a new password, this password will rotate monthly and be posted in #/g/ftp on our irc.</li><li>We also plan on changing which web irc clients will be permitted to access our irc server, soon it will be just our own ran webirc client, sorry.</li><li>Our main site will return shortly, probably with some new design. </li><li>Some new more clear cut rules, apparently some do not know doxxing without permission is bad.</li></ul>


<br/><br/><br/>For now that is all, please if you have any questions you should now how to contact me.<br/><br/>Also if you really desire to see a real shit thread you can view that <a href="http://rbt.asia/g/thread/36825476">here</a>, most of that thread is speculation and lies.  But hey you&#8217;re gonna believe what you&#8217;re gonna believe. <br/><br/>I am sorry for the downtime of our loyal users.

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[/g/mail move successful, welcome to the Netherlands]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/21/g-mail-move-successful-welcome-to-the-netherlands/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/21/g-mail-move-successful-welcome-to-the-netherlands</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our /g/mail service has successfully been transferred to a box in the Netherlands.  Most should the notice the service is all more responsive as we have significantly upgraded the server running /g/mail and the mailing lists.<br/></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[/g/mail Downtime]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/g-mail-downtime/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/g-mail-downtime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There will be a 30 minute downtime for our mail service today at around 9 a.m. EST.  We are moving the server to a new location in the Netherlands as well as upgrading the server resources. <br/><br/>Also there will be a new IP address for the server/service though DNS will be updated so everything so continue to &#8220;just work&#8221;.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[FTP downtime]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/ftp-downtime/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/ftp-downtime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our beloved FTP service will be down until a decision can be made on the course it will take.  Please know all the data is safe and will return.<br/><br/>We are just waiting for a &#8220;shitstorm&#8221; to blow over.  Our main page will return soon as well.   All is okay.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mailing Lists and the new bot.]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/mailing-lists-and-the-new-bot/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/15/mailing-lists-and-the-new-bot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I have successfully setup and added our own mailing lists server.  It is at <a href="http://lists.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://lists.installgentoo.com">http://lists.installgentoo.com</a></a>.  Please sign up for our announcements list to stay up to date on news for installgentoo.com.  I have also added the mailing list lel, for general fun and just playing with mailing lists.<br/><br/>If anyone can think of other lists, or would like a list for their own project please let me know.<br/><br/>Also I need to mention that I have updated our beloved gtrackerbot, now gtrackerbot3.  It is a tweaked jenni/phenny bot that eventually I will repost the source for.  We are also currently tweaking and playing with a gazelle irc bot so that it can directly interface with our tracker.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tracker torrent posting issues]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/14/tracker-torrent-posting-issues/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/14/tracker-torrent-posting-issues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have heard from many of our /g/tracker users that when the upload a torrent it does not show up on the site.  Then a few hours later it does.<br/><br/>The issue that is happening is our memcache of the site is a bit slow.  I will be looking at tweaking soon to fix the delay in torrents appearing so please bear with.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/13/big-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/13/big-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been very, very busy as of late but have managed to make several changes behind the scenes.  This includes adding services, changing services, and removing services.  I thought it would be best to explain in a post all of the changes instead of several.<br/><br/><b>Changes:</b><br/>Last week we successfully moved the ftp, tracker, and blogs to a much more powerful server.  So you should notice those services are quite quicker.<br/><br/><b>Things going away/already gone:</b><br/><br/></p>


<ul><li><a href="http://chan.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://chan.installgentoo.com">http://chan.installgentoo.com</a></a> - not enough interest</li><li><a href="http://radio.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://radio.installgentoo.com">http://radio.installgentoo.com</a></a> - icecast is really great but not enough interest to dj and listen</li></ul>


<br/><br/><br/><b>New things:</b><br/><br/><ul><li><a href="http://status.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://status.installgentoo.com">http://status.installgentoo.com</a></a> - is now our blogger status blog, status was running on an amazon ec2 instance but now that our free tier is running out we needed to find an alternative.  </li><li><a href="http://servers.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://servers.installgentoo.com">http://servers.installgentoo.com</a></a> - the 2nd half of our status site was the server checker, this has been moved off of ec2 and installed on a free web host (for now).</li><li>mumble.installgentoo.com - now is set for max audio quality </li><li><a href="http://music.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://music.installgentoo.com">http://music.installgentoo.com</a></a> - is back by popular demand, still in beta testing but this is now a subsonic instance streaming the ftp music folder.</li><li><a href="http://archive.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://archive.installgentoo.com">http://archive.installgentoo.com</a></a> - is back as well but this time as a nice foolfuuka archiver, for now we are just archiving /g/ those this will probably change.  Also on this site is /IG/ and a spot for our own chan (like chan.IG), I will probably redirect chan.installgentoo.com here.</li><li><a href="http://bb.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://bb.installgentoo.com">http://bb.installgentoo.com</a></a> - a more persistent form of communication and community is being tested and tweaked, so this is coming soon.</li><li>New ftp status pages: <a href="http://ftp.installgentoo.com/vnstat/"><a href="http://ftp.installgentoo.com/vnstat/">http://ftp.installgentoo.com/vnstat/</a></a> and <a href="http://ftp.installgentoo.com/sysinfo/"><a href="http://ftp.installgentoo.com/sysinfo/">http://ftp.installgentoo.com/sysinfo/</a></a></li><li><a href="http://etherpad.installgentoo.com/"><a href="http://etherpad.installgentoo.com">http://etherpad.installgentoo.com</a></a> - just another etherpad instance</li><li>nntp://news.installgentoo.com - our own private usenet server (local groups only), I will be making a tutorial on how to connect soon.</li></ul><br/><br/>Well, I think that about covers everything.

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Server Migration Complete]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/07/server-migration-complete/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/07/server-migration-complete</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our migration to a more powerful server for the ftp, tracker, and blog site has completed successfully.  With this move we have discontinued radio.IG and we will probably be bringing back music.IG instead.<br/><br/> <br/><br/>Stay tuned.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Services]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/07/new-services/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/07/new-services</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New services!<br/><br/>New foolfuuka archiver! <a href="http://archive.installgentoo.com">http://archive.installgentoo.com</a> currently it is only archiving /g/ but this will change in the future.<br/><br/>NNTP server for newsgroups is back.  news.installgentoo.com, I will post a short video to explain how to connect to this service soon.<br/><br/> </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Etherpad Service Requested]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/01/etherpad-service-requested/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/09/01/etherpad-service-requested</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By popular request, and that I think its a nice service.  Etherpad.installgentoo.com has been added to our stable of services.<br/><br/> <br/><br/>enjoy</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mumble server fixed.]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/24/mumble-server-fixed/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/24/mumble-server-fixed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You will have a notification about a cert change, this is safe.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[mumble server]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/24/mumble-server/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/24/mumble-server</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>the mumble server is currently down as we work to fix whatever has happened to it.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Planned Down Time - Friday]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/22/planned-down-time-friday/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/22/planned-down-time-friday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Friday between 2 - 10&#160;pm EST we expect around 15 minutes of downtime for the following:<br/><br/>irc, /g/mail, vidya, mumble, jabber, main website.<br/><br/> <br/><br/>Our provider is changing out the SSDs these services are stored on and should only last 15 minutes though there is a large window.<br/><br/> <br/><br/>Please stay tuned.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Change in down time]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/22/change-in-down-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/22/change-in-down-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay downtime now should be any moment now and should only last a few minutes.  This again will only affect the services listed in the previous blog post.<br/><br/> <br/><br/>We are moving are boxes to another server in order to avoid down time tomorrow and get more disk space out of it.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mail downtime]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/12/mail-downtime/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-12T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/08/12/mail-downtime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Planned maintenence on all of our servers is now complete, we have succesfully moved all mail services to our unified email server.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mumble server moved]]></title>
    <link href="http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/07/26/mumble-server-moved/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://installgentoostatus.github.io/blog/2013/07/26/mumble-server-moved</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have moved the mumble server to a different server to provide better access and consistent service.  The interruption may be minimal as our dns entries change.  Do not be alarmed as you will have to regenerate certificates with the new server.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
